<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Financial Freedom</string>
    <string name="credit">Based on \"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason</string>
    <string name="titlePart1">Steps towards</string>
    <string name="titlePart2">Financial Freedom</string>

    <string name="step0no">0</string>
    <string name="step0text">Financial Freedom</string>

    <string name="step1no">1</string>
    <string name="step1text">Start Saving</string>

    <string name="step2no">2</string>
    <string name="step2text">Control Expenses</string>

    <string name="step3no">3</string>
    <string name="step3text">Put Money to Work</string>

    <string name="step4no">4</string>
    <string name="step4text">Guard Treasures</string>

    <string name="step5no">5</string>
    <string name="step5text">Profit from Dwelling</string>

    <string name="step6no">6</string>
    <string name="step6text">Future Income</string>

    <string name="step7no">7</string>
    <string name="step7text">Increase Ability</string>

    <string name="super1">&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;</string>
    <string name="citation1">&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason</string>
    <string name="super2">&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;2&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;</string>
    <string name="citation2">%1$s\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason</string>

    <string name="title_activity_steps">Financial Steps</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string-array name="step_numbers">
        <item/>
        <item>@string/step1no</item>
        <item>@string/step2no</item>
        <item>@string/step3no</item>
        <item>@string/step4no</item>
        <item>@string/step5no</item>
        <item>@string/step6no</item>
        <item>@string/step7no</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="step_short_title">
        <item>@string/step0text</item>
        <item>@string/step1text</item>
        <item>@string/step2text</item>
        <item>@string/step3text</item>
        <item>@string/step4text</item>
        <item>@string/step5text</item>
        <item>@string/step6text</item>
        <item>@string/step7text</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="step_long_title">
        <item>What is Financial Freedom?</item>
        <item>Start saving money</item>
        <item>Control your expenditures</item>
        <item>Make your money to multiply</item>
        <item>Guard your money from loss</item>
        <item>Make your dwelling a profitable investment</item>
        <item>Insure a future income</item>
        <item>Increase your ability to earn</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="step_quotes">
        <item>the state of having sufficient personal wealth to live, without having to work actively for basic necessities.%1$s</item>
        <item>For each ten coins I put in, to spend but nine.%1$s</item>
        <item>Budget thy expenses that thou mayest have coins to pay for thy necessities, to pay for thy enjoyments and to gratify thy worthwhile desires without spending more than nine-tenths of thy earnings.%1$s</item>
        <item>Put each coin to laboring that it may reproduce its kind even as the flocks of the field and help bring to thee income, a stream of wealth that shall flow constantly into thy purse.%1$s</item>
        <item>Guard thy treasure from loss by investing only where thy principal is safe, where it may be reclaimed if desirable, and where thou will not fail to collect a fair rental. Consult with wise men. Secure the advice of those experienced in the profitable handling of gold. Let their wisdom protect thy treasure from unsafe investments.%1$s</item>
        <item>Own thy own home.%1$s</item>
        <item>Provide in advance for the needs of thy growing age and the protection of thy family.%1$s</item>
        <item>Cultivate thy own powers, to study and become wiser, to become more skillful, to so act as to respect thyself.%1$s</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="step_text" formatted="false">
        <item>&lt;p&gt;Financial freedom is the goal, the 7 steps are meant to help you attain that goal. They set forth a starting point,
            you need to save and control your expenditures, but also contains growth features like putting your money to work or increasing
            your ability to earn. If you learn them, understand them, and then live them, I believe they will help you attain financial freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;But what is Financial Freedom?  Is it a large amount of money? At one point I thought so, but now I say it is not. A large
            amount of money will give you freedom for a period of time, but as you spend it, it will decrease and eventually be gone. Financial
            Freedom comes from the ownership of income streams that don’t rely on your actions to exists.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;I conducted two experiments. In the first experiment, I quit my job with what I thought was a large amount of money,
            I invested in the stock market, and got reasonable returns. However, in two years nearly all of it was gone. The returns were not high
            enough to pay my expenses so every month the amount of cash I had decreased. I thought I had some freedom financially because of the
            money I had, and for a short time I did. However, once the money was gone so was the freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Over the following ten years I worked on ways to create an income independent from working my job. My perception on money
            had changed. Because of the teachings of the first experiment, I was now saving at a much higher rate. I was investing the money into
            assets that generate a cash flow, mostly bonds, and dividend stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Two years ago I started the second experiment. I quit my job with an income. Because of the income, I can continue my
            sabbatical or go back to work. It is my choice. And that choice is freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Wikipedia
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
        <item>&lt;p&gt;If one labors and earns he/she should begin to save money. This is the first step towards financial freedom.
            It is wise to utilize current sources of income to grow one’s wealth, saving a minimum of 10&#37; of their income.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;This should be committed to and done, prior to spending.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;By merely saving money on a regular basis, your wealth will grow.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
        <item>
            &lt;p&gt;Many say that their expenditures are too high to be able to afford money for saving. We know that not all people earn the same amount of
                money, some earn much more. There are those with families, and those without. Yet no-one seems to have any money saved.  One tends to adjust to
                their level of income nearly regardless of the amounts. I have known people making hundreds of thousands of dollars and having little money saved.
                While knowing people making $10/hour saving over 10&#37; of their income.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Unless we fight it, our ‘necessary expenses’ will always grow to the level of our income.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Controlling your expenditures is about choice, it is about fighting that human nature to grow to the level of our income.
            A budgeting process is a tool to help use determine where we are spending valuable resources.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Controlling your expense should not be viewed as chains that bind you to sacrifice but as choices made that will help liberate you
            in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;As I get older and I have some financial freedom, I have found that I have so many more options and choices over my colleagues.
            I have more money to spend when I am working, have a good amount of emergency funds should something happen, and can choose to work at a job
            that pays less that I enjoy more, all because I chose to control my expenditures and followed the other steps.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Review your expenditures and eliminate or reduce the items that are unnecessary expenses that bring little or diminishing joy.
            Minimize your expenditures to no more than 90&#37; of your income.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
        <item>
            &lt;p&gt;If you save $100 a month, your savings will grow over time, and in 12 months you will have $1,200. By investing your savings, your money will
            start to generate an income, and this income will help you grow your wealth over time.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;There is a lot of information about compounding interest available, it is worth reading and understanding. When your money is working for
            you time is a great asset.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Work: Income is created from work. As an employee that income is in the form of your pay check. But money is an inanimate object,
            how can it work for you?&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Jim is a chicken farmer. He has 100 birds and wants to expand to 200. He wants to borrow your $1,200 to expand. He is willing to pay
            you 10&#37; interest to borrow your money for a year. You decide to invest, putting your money to “work”. It’s Jim’s actual work that creates the
            income for your money. But let’s not forget the chickens. They are reproducing and laying eggs to be sold.  They are working with Jim to pay you as
            well. Jim need the money to purchase a machine that cleans the eggs, making him more productive and giving him the ability to manage 200 chickens.
            That machine is also working to pay you back. (Even though it is an inanimate object.)&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;I tell this story to point out that there is work behind investments. And to be financially independent you may find success in thinking
            about this work and how it can benefit you. Tenets work to pay rent. If they can’t earn enough you will receive lower rents or have empty
            apartments.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;There are many ways to put money to work, bonds receiving an interest payment, stock with dividends and/or capital gains, rental properties,
            or royalties. Even buying chickens and selling the eggs.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
        <item>
            &lt;p&gt;It is very important to guard your money from loss, else you run the risk of losing it just as if you had never saved it in the
            first place. It is wise advice to invest in what you know and to seek the advice of professionals in the area you look to invest.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;There is a lot of emotion in investing, it is best to check the dreams at the door. And try to be critical when assessing potential
            investments. Sometimes it is worth staying away from opportunities when you get caught up in the emotions and cannot see clearly, even when
            others seem to be making money.  Don’t forget the old adage, if it looks too good to be true, it probably is.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
        <item>
            &lt;p&gt;Owning your own dwelling is a good way to save. Each month when the mortgage is paid, part of the principal is paid along with the interest.
            Once the loan is paid off, your expenses decrease freeing up more money to save or requiring less income for financial freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Looking at a dwelling as an investment can be dangerous. In most cases, money put into a house will not work for the owner,
            providing an income. (Step 3) Also, as shown in recent years, the house may and may not appreciate in value.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Owning your dwelling can still be a good idea. Be careful not to overbuy, buying way to much house just because you can afford it.
            This can make your house a bad investment, by ignoring “controlling your expenditures” (step 2).&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;There are also ways to make your dwelling a true investment, generating income.  The most popular, buying a two family house.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
        <item>
            &lt;p&gt;Thinking about the future is not just retirement. Yes you will want to retire someday and during that time, you will want to
            have the resources to live the life you want.You should think about retirement and plan accordingly. It is good to save the maximum
            amount in retirement accounts to maximize tax advantages. But do not lose sight of the fact that there could be a non-retirement opportunity
            that is financially more advantageous than putting money in retirement accounts. Always consider company matching of money in any analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Just as important to your future is your financial condition if you should lose your job, an emergency happens in your or a loved
            one’s life, or an opportunity arises that requires financial assets. To me this is one of the major goals of financial freedom: to be prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
        <item>
            &lt;p&gt;Increasing your ability to earn is where creativity, education, and experimentation advance your path to financial freedom.
            Fundamentally its direction is to find ways to increase your knowledge and skills in generating wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Finding more money to save could be done by increasing your income. You can improve skills, take classes, attend to your boss’
            needs, take on new responsibility, get a new job etc. By finding ways to improve yourself you can generally attain more income,
            increasing resources available to save. Alternatively, increasing your abilities can also help in controlling expenses. Growing up
            we had little money, my father controlled his expenses through hunting. He enjoyed it, while the costs were low, it provided hundreds
            of pounds of meat.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Always strive for improvement it will most likely help you improve your financial condition, and it will make you feel
            proud of what you can accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            ------&lt;br/&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;1&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;\"The Richest Man in Babylon\" by George S. Clason
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
